[music]
[Instructor] Great, now our Player
character animations
are in a really good place.
We have our Running animations,
and then when we jump,
you can see we jump for joy,
but we have this weird little issue
where when we jump,
the animation stops short,
and then we start running in the air,
which doesn't really look right.
So we're actually going to go
into our "Running_Jump" animation,
and similarly to how we set
the "Speed"
to be a little bit faster
for the run
to just make it look like
the Player's running faster,
we're going to set our animation
Speed just a bit slower.
We'll do a 0.7,
just so that the animation now runs
just a bit longer,
instead of faster,
so when we press Play,
now when we jump,
the animation definitely works
a lot better; it lasts a bit longer.
I think one thing that we're going to do
just to make it look
a little bit more realistic
is we're actually going to go
into our Player Object,
and we're going to Play around
with some of the variables,
so specifically our "Mass,"
our "Jump Force,"
and our "Gravity Modifier"
to just make it look
a lot more realistic,
and better for what we want it to be.
So our Mass on our Rigidbody
is a little low.
People don't normally
weigh just 1 kilogram,
so we're going to change our Mass.
Usually, on average, a person
weighs about 60 kilograms or so,
so we'll see what
that does when we press Play.
And we have the jumping animation,
but we don't really,
we don't really go anywhere.
So let's play around
with the Jump Force a little bit.
Maybe let's edit to...
a little bit over,
like 10 times the actual Mass.
So we'll do like a 700.
We'll see how that looks.
Ooh, I got it a little bit high.
So maybe, let's see,
if we go to our Gravity Modifier,
let's make it a little bit,
let's make it a little bit more.
Let's make it like a 1.5.
And now when we jump,
not bad...
Pretty close. So we could probably
fiddle with these values a bit more,
but it looks pretty good.
We get pretty close to the Ground
before we start running.
So now what you're going to do is
in your Player Animator window,
if you go to the Jumping Layer,
and then we click on the Running_Jump.
So we'll set the animation
Speed to be a little bit slower.
So I set mine to 0.7.
And then on our Player Object,
we're going to make
the Player weigh a bit more,
so let's make it about
60 or so kilograms.
We pushed up the Jump Force
up to 700.
And then we increased
Gravity just a little bit,
so we set it to about 1.5
so the Player falls
a little bit faster when they reach
the Ground.
Now it's your turn.
[music]